Their crime is curiosity.
Hackers is a action, crime, thriller film directed by Iain Softley.
Along with his new friends, a teenager who was arrested by the US Secret Service and banned from using a computer for writing a computer virus discovers a plot by a nefarious
hacker, but they must use their computer skills to find the evidence while being pursued by the Secret Service and the evil computer genius behind the virus.
Dade Murphy / 'Crash Override' / 'Zero Cool', played by Jonny Lee Miller.
Kate Libby / 'Acid Burn', played by Angelina Jolie.
Emmanuelle Goldstein / 'Cereal Killer', played by Matthew Lillard.
Joey Pardella, played by Jesse Bradford.
Ramon Sanchez / 'Phantom Phreak', played by Renoly Santiago.
Paul Cook / 'Lord Nikon', played by Laurence Mason.
Hackers is a 1995 American crime thriller film directed by Iain Softley and starring Jonny Lee Miller, Angelina Jolie,
Jesse Bradford, Matthew Lillard, Laurence Mason, Renoly Santiago, Lorraine Bracco, and Fisher Stevens.
The film follows a group of high school hackers and
their involvement in an attempted theft.
Made in the mid-1990s when the Internet was just starting to become popular among the general public, it
reflects the ideals laid out in the Hacker Manifesto quoted in the film: "This is our world now...
the world of the electron and the switch...
We exist without skin color, without nationality, without religious bias...
and you call us criminals...
Yes, I am a criminal.
My crime is that of curiosity."
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and underperformed
at the box office upon release, but has gone on to achieve cult classic status.
The film explores themes of new york city, computer,
hacker, computer virus, virtual reality.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and intense.